Guide to the Arnold Carl Klebs Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Arnold Carl Klebs papers
1850-1947
MS 1297
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
30.5
(30 boxes, 1 folio)
The papers consist of correspondence, research notes, manuscripts, printed matter, and photographs.
Klebs, Arnold C. (Arnold Carl), 1870-1943
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale University Medical Historical Library, 1980, 1987.
Associated Materials
Associated material: Arnold Carl Klebs Papers, Yale University Medical Historical Library.
Biographical / Historical
Arnold-Carl Klebs, a distinguished medical bibliographer, historian, and specialist in the field of tuberculosis, was born in Berne, Switzerland, on March 17, 1870. He received his early education at the Gymnasia of Prague and Zurich. After academic studies in Berlin, Prague, Wurtzburg, Berne, and Basel, he received his bachelor's degree from the University of Zurich in 1888. He received his M.D. degree from Basel in 1895, serving there as an assistant in the Polyclinic. He also worked as an instructor in pathology at Zurich.
Klebs came to the United States in 1896 and became a United States citizen in 1904. His father Edwin Klebs, co-discoverer with Loeffler of the bacterium responsible for diptheria, had taken a post in pathology in Asheville, North Carolina. Klebs decided to settle as a tuberculosis specialist in Chicago, where he remained until 1909. In that year he edited a comprehensive treatise on tuberculosis. Klebs served as consulting physician to Cook County Hospital and director of the Chicago Tuberculosis Institute. In 1912 Klebs was vice-president of the section on preventable diseases at the International Congress of Hygiene held in Washington, D.C.
Klebs then retired to Switzerland, where for the next thirty years he studied and collected in the field of medical and scientific bibliography, primarily works of the fifteenth century. In 1938 he issued a short title bibliography Incunabula Scientifica et Medica. His other historical writings include papers on Leonardo da Vinci, early herbals, remedies against the pest, and specialized bibliographic studies.
Klebs maintained a life-long friendship with Harvey Cushing, with whom he shared his enthusiasm for all phases of medical history and bibliography. When Cushing announced his intention to leave his library to Yale University, Klebs also agreed to donate his collection to the university.
In June, 1898, Klebs married Margaret Forbes, who died a year later. Klebs had one child by this marriage, Sarah Forbes Klebs, who married the Rev. George Stewart. He married Harriet K. Newell in May, 1909. Arnold Klebs died on March 6, 1943, in Nyon, Switzerland.
Extracted from a Yale University News Bureau press release of March 8, 1943.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, research notes, manuscripts, printed matter, and photographs.
Incunabula; Medicine -- Bibliography; Medicine -- History; Klebs, Arnold C. (Arnold Carl), 1870-1943
- Inventory, Circa 1850-1947; 29.5 linear feet (29 boxes, 1 folio)
  Scope and Contents
  Received from: Yale Medical Historical Library, 1980
  The Arnold Carl Klebs Papers are roughly sorted by type of material: Subject Files; Correspondence; Writings; Card Files; Glass Negatives and Printing Blocks; and Oversize. The material has been left in the order as it was received from the Medical Historical Library.
  The listing which follows includes all folder or card file titles. An asterisk (*) has been used next to a folder title to indicate that additional material by the same title will be found elsewhere in the listing.
  Additional Klebs Papers remain in the Medical Historical Library.
  - Subject file I
    - Abraham ben Ezra (*) (Box 1)
    - Abulcasis (*) (Box 1)
    - Albide Brudzewo (Box 1)
    - Albertus Magnus (*) (Box 1)
    - Albert der Grosse (*) (Box 1)
    - Albert, Meister (Box 1)
    - Albich, Siegmund (*) (Box 1)
    - Albumasar (*) (Box 1)
    - Alcaniz (*) (Box 1)
    - Aldobrandino (*) (Box 1)
    - Alfonso X el Sabio (*) (Box 1)
    - Andrea, Antonio (*) (Box 1)
    - Andreas Hispanus (Box 1)
    - Anianus (*) (Box 1)
    - Arcolani, Giovanni (*) (Box 1)
    - Ardoini, Sante (*) (Box 1)
    - Aristotle (*) (Box 1)
    - Arnold de Villanova (*) (Box 1)
    - Articella (*) (Box 1)
    - Augustone, Giov. Basil (*) (Box 1)
    - Augusti (*) (Box 1)
    - Averroes (*) (Box 1)
    - Avicenna (*) (Box 1)
    - Avogario, Pietro Bono (*) (Box 1)
    - Bartholomew the Englishman (*) (Box 1)
    - Burkhard von Horneck (*) (Box 1)
    - Bavera (Pest) (Box 1)
    - [Benham] Kalendazii (Box 1)
    - Bellanti, Lucio (*) (Box 1)
    - Benedetto da Norcia (*) (Box 1)
    - Benedetti, Alessandro (*) (Box 1)
    - Berlinghieri (*) (Box 1)
    - Bernard de Gordon (*) (Box 1)
    - Biblia (Box 1)
    - Boethius (*) (Box 1)
    - Bonihomini, Alf. (*) (Box 1)
    - Brant, Sebastian (*) (Box 1)
    - Breydenbach (*) (Box 1)
    - Brunschwig (*) (Box 1)
    - Canutus (*) (Box 1)
    - Calendrier (Box 1)
    - Catone, Angelo (Box 1)
    - Calandri (*) (Box 1)
    - Cecco d'Ascoli (*) (Box 1)
    - Celsus (*) (Box 1)
    - Cermisone (*) (Box 1)
    - Champier (*) (Box 1)
    - Conrad von Megenberg (*) (Box 1)
    - Columella (*) (Box 1)
    - ACK Pest (Box 1)
    - Cyclopius, Cyoneus Guolfus (*) (Box 1)
    - Chappusius Nicolaus (Box 1)
    - Compost (*) (Box 1)
    - Collenuccio, Pandolfo (*) (Box 1)
    - Danse Macabre des Hommes/Femmes (Box 1)
    - Decembrio, Pierro Candido (*) (Box 1)
    - Despars, Jacques (*) (Box 1)
    - Dino del Garbo (*) (Box 1)
    - Diogenes Cynicus (*) (Box 1)
    - Dondi (*) (Box 1)
    - Eaux Artificielles (*) (Box 1)
    - Epidemia (*) (Box 1)
    - Eyb, Albrecht (*) (Box 1)
    - Faber, Wenzel, von Budweis (*) (Box 1)
    - Falcucci, Nicolo (*) (Box 1)
    - Febris (*) (Box 1)
    - (Ferrari da) Gradi (*) (Box 1)
    - Fenestella (Box 1)
    - Ficino, Marsilio (*) (Box 1)
    - Franciscus de la Pergula (Box 1)
    - Francisc. de Senis (Box 1)
    - Gambiglione, Angelo de (*) (Box 1)
    - Gaddesden, John of (*) (Box 1)
    - Gentile da Foligno (*) (Box 1)
    - Gerson, John (Box 1)
    - Johannes Itrensis (Box 1)
    - Granollachs, Bernat de (*) (Box 1)
    - Grapaldi, Franc. Mario (*) (Box 1)
    - Grassus, Benvenutus (*) (Box 1)
    - Gresemund, Dietrich (*) (Box 1)
    - Grunpeck (*) (Box 1)
    - Guainerio, Antonio (Box 1)
    - Guglielmo da Saliceto (Box 1)
    - Guy de Chauliac (Box 1)
    - Haly Abbas (Box 1)
    - Heberling, Joh. (Box 1)
    - Herbals (Box 1)
    - Hundt, M. (Box 1)
    - Hippocrates (Box 1)
    - Jacme, Jean (Box 2)
    - Jacme, d'Agramont (Box 2)
    - Jacopo da Forli (Box 2)
    - Johannes de Nova Ilomo (Box 2)
    - Rudolph Juchhoff (Box 2)
    - Ketham (Box 2)
    - Lanflane de Milan (Box 2)
    - Leforestier, Thomas (Box 2)
    - LeGrand, Jacques (Box 2)
    - Lul, Ramon (Box 2)
    - Lucidarius (Box 2)
    - Lucretius (Box 2)
    - Luntis, Bernardinus de (Box 2)
    - Maccagno, Domenico (Box 2)
    - Magninus (Box 2)
    - Mainardi, Giovanni (Box 2)
    - Maiolo, Lorenzo (Box 2)
    - Mandeville (Box 2)
    - Manifredi, Girolamo (Box 2)
    - Marliani, Giovanni (Box 2)
    - Martius, Galeottus (Box 2)
    - Matteolo da Perugia (Box 2)
    - Mensa Philosophica (Box 2)
    - Mercurius, Contra (Box 2)
    - Merula, Giorgio (Box 2)
    - Mondino (Box 2)
    - Mesue (Box 2)
    - Molitor (Box 2)
    - Montagnana (Box 2)
    - M, misc. (Box 2)
    - Nicephoros (Box 2)
    - Nicolaus Saleznitanus (Box 2)
    - Nifo, Agostino (Box 2)
    - Oliverius (Box 2)
    - Ortoloff (Box 2)
    - Pacioli, Luca da Borgo (Box 2)
    - Pantaleone (*) (Box 2)
    - Peckham (Box 2)
    - Petroleon (*) (Box 2)
    - Petrus Hispanus (Box 2)
    - Pico Della Mirandola (Box 2)
    - Pier Adam [Micheli] (Box 2)
    - Pietro d'Abano (*) (Box 2)
    - Pietro da Tossignano (Box 2)
    - Platina [Bartolomeo Sacci] (Box 2)
    - Pliny (Box 2)
    - Prevost, Nicole (Box 2)
    - Proliano, Christiano (*) (Box 2)
    - Ptolemy (Box 2)
    - Publicio, Jacopo (Box 2)
    - Razi (Box 2)
    - Regimen Sanitaris (Box 2)
    - Regiomonatanus (Box 2)
    - Ramis de Pareja (Box 2)
    - Rodericus Zamorensis (Box 2)
    - Rolevnick (Box 2)
    - Robert the Englishman (Box 2)
    - Rogerius/Rolandus (Box 2)
    - Rudimentum Noritorium (*) (Box 2)
    - Salamon Negri/Syllanus (Box 3)
    - Sacrobosco (Box 3)
    - Savonarola, Michele (Box 3)
    - Schrick, Michael (*) (Box 3)
    - Schynagel, Marcus (Box 3)
    - Simon of Genoa (Box 3)
    - Simon Januensis (Box 3)
    - Sommariva, Giorgio (Box 3)
    - Steinhoewel (Box 3)
    - Strimerio, Giovanni Battista (Box 3)
    - Summaire de Medicine (Box 3)
    - Swineshead/Calculator (Box 3)
    - Scotus, Michael (Box 3)
    - Serenus, Samonicus Quintus (Box 3)
    - Sermoneta, Giovanni (Box 3)
    - Silvatico, Matteo (Box 3)
    - S, misc. (Box 3)
    - Testamento Preservativo (Box 3)
    - Taillevent (Box 3)
    - Tura de Castello (Box 3)
    - Tractatus de Urinis (Box 3)
    - Tractar von der Rotlichen Sucht der Pestilenz ( Pest ) (Tract on the Red Disease of Pestilence) (Box 3)
    - Toscani, Luigi (Box 3)
    - Torella (Box 3)
    - Torquemado (Box 3)
    - Thurecensis (Box 3)
    - Theophrastus (Box 3)
    - Tornius (Box 3)
    - Thomas of Aquino (Box 3)
    - Ugo da Siena (*) (Box 3)
    - Ulsen, Dietrich (Box 3)
    - Valasco de Tazenta (*) (Box 3)
    - Valla, Georgio (Box 3)
    - Varia (Box 3)
    - Valturio, Roberto (Box 3)
    - Vegetius (Box 3)
    - Vincentius Ferrer (Box 3)
    - Vincent de Beauvais (Box 3)
    - Vocabulaire Latin-Francaise (Box 3)
    - [Peter Wagner] (Box 3)
    - Zacuto, Abraham (Box 3)
    - Zainer, Johannes (Box 3)
    - Zeno (Box 3)
    - Zerbi, Gabriele (*) (Box 3)
    - Latin Notes Series} title illegible (Box 3)
    - Greek Notes Series} title illegible (Box 3)
    - Sudhoff Collection (*) (Box 3)
    - Desiderata (*) (Box 3)
    - Incunabula (Box 3)
    - More Notes, A-Z (Box 3)
    - Rudimentum/Mer de Histoires (*) (Box 3)
    - Arbolayre (*) (Box 3)
    - Ellenbog, Ulrich (*) (Box 3)
  - Subject File II
    - Abraham ben Ezra (*) (Box 4)
    - Abulcasis (*) (Box 4)
    - Achillini, Alessandro (Box 4)
    - Adelard of Bath (Box 4)
    - Abiosi, Giovanni B. (Box 4)
    - Albert the Great (*) (Box 4)
    - Albert von Sachsen (Box 4)
    - Alberti, Leone Battista (Box 4)
    - Alberto da Gandino (Box 4)
    - Albich, Siegmund (*) (Box 4)
    - Albohazen (Box 4)
    - Albubathar (Box 4)
    - Albumasar (*) (Box 4)
    - Alcaniz (*) (Box 4)
    - Alchabitus (Box 4)
    - Aldobrandino da Siena (*) (Box 4)
    - Alexander of Aphrodisias (Box 4)
    - Alexander [of Hales] (Box 4)
    - Alphonso de Carragena (Box 4)
    - Alphonso de Cordova (Box 4)
    - Alphonso Vargas de Toledo (Box 4)
    - Alphonso X de Sabio (*) (Box 4)
    - Alfraganus (Box 4)
    - Algorithmus (Box 4)
    - Aliboron (Box 4)
    - Alicardian (Box 4)
    - Almansor (Box 4)
    - Alvarez, Fernando (Box 4)
    - Amadeo de Tortona (Box 4)
    - Audolo di Negro (Box 4)
    - Andrea, Antonio (*) (Box 4)
    - Andrelini, Publio Fausto (Box 4)
    - Andres de Li (Box 4)
    - Angeli de Ulma (Box 4)
    - Angelo da Fossombrone (Box 4)
    - Anianus (*) (Box 4)
    - Antonius Pius (Box 4)
    - Antonio de Lebrija (Box 4)
    - Aphormisms (Box 4)
    - Apicius (Box 4)
    - Apuleisus (Box 4)
    - Aratos (Box 4)
    - Arcana Medicinae (Box 4)
    - Arcolani, Giovanni (*) (Box 4)
    - Ardoino, Santa (*) (Box 4)
    - Aristarchos (Box 4)
    - Aristotle (*) (Box 4)
    - Arithmetica Textus (Box 4)
    - Arnold de Villanova (*) (Box 4)
    - Arnaudus (Box 4)
    - Arquato, Antonio (Box 4)
    - Ars Memorativa (Box 4)
    - Ars et Modus Vitae (Box 4)
    - Arstedyge, Boeck (Box 4)
    - Artaldo, Giovanni (Box 4)
    - Articella (*) (Box 4)
    - Arzuei, Gute/Rechte/Wider Pest (Box 4)
    - Astrolabium (Box 4)
    - Auctoritates, Aristotelis (Box 4)
    - Augusti, Cyrice degli (*) (Box 4)
    - Augustinus, Moravus (Box 4)
    - Augustone, Giovanni B. (*) (Box 4)
    - Avenzoar (Box 4)
    - Averroes (*) (Box 4)
    - Avienus, Rufus Festus (Box 4)
    - Avogario, Pietro Bono (*) (Box 4)
    - Avicenna (*) (Box 4)
    - Badet, Armand (Box 4)
    - Bagellardi (Box 4)
    - Balaguer, Nicholas (Box 4)
    - Baldini, Baldino de (Box 4)
    - Baldouinus (Box 4)
    - Barbaro, Ermolao (Box 4)
    - Barbo, Giovanni (Box 4)
    - Bartholomeus Usingen (Box 4)
    - Bartholomew the Englishman (*) (Box 4)
    - Bartolo da Sassoferrato (Box 4)
    - Bartolomeo da Pisa (Box 4)
    - Bartolomeo da li Sonetti (Box 4)
    - Barzizza, Cristoforo (Box 4)
    - Basin, Bernard (Box 4)
    - Bassino, Giovanni Antonio (Box 4)
    - Baverii, Baverio de (Box 4)
    - Bede (Box 4)
    - Begani, Agostino (Box 4)
    - Beldomandi, Prosdocimo de (Box 4)
    - Bellanti, Lucio (*) (Box 4)
    - Bembo, Pietro (Box 4)
    - Bendinelli, Matteo de (Box 4)
    - Benedetti, Alessandro (*) (Box 4)
    - Benedetto da Norcia (*) (Box 4)
    - Benignus Cisterciensis (Box 4)
    - Berlingeri, Francesco (*) (Box 4)
    - Bernard de Gordon (*) (Box 4)
    - Bernardino da Landriano (Box 4)
    - Bernardus de Cracovia (Box 4)
    - Beroaldo, Filippo (Box 4)
    - Bianchi, Giuliano (Box 4)
    - Bianchini, Giovanni (Box 4)
    - Boccaccio, Giovanni (Box 4)
    - Boethus (*) (Box 4)
    - Bonaccioli, Ludovico (Box 4)
    - Bonamoneta (Box 4)
    - Bonatti, Guido (Box 4)
    - Bonaventura de Brixia (Box 4)
    - Bonet de Lattes (Box 4)
    - Bonet, Nicholas (Box 4)
    - Bonhominis, Alphonso (*) (Box 4)
    - Bonincontri, Lorenzo (Box 4)
    - Bonsignis, Bonasignia de (Box 4)
    - Borghi, Pietro (Box 4)
    - Bracelli, Giacomo (Box 4)
    - Brack, Wenceslaus (Box 4)
    - Bradwardin, Thomas (Box 4)
    - Brant, Sebatian (*) (Box 4)
    - Brasca, Santo (Box 4)
    - Breydenbach, Bernhard von (*) (Box 4)
    - Bricot (Box 4)
    - Bruni, Francesco (Box 4)
    - Brunus, Bertrand (Box 4)
    - Brunschwig (*) (Box 4)
    - Buchlein (Box 4)
    - Burkhard von Horneck (*) (Box 4)
    - Burley, Walter (Box 4)
    - Burzio, Nicolo (Box 4)
    - Caballo, Francesco (Box 4)
    - Calandri, Filippo (*) (Box 4)
    - Calderini, Domizio (Box 4)
    - Calendarium (Box 4)
    - Campis, Petrus de (Box 4)
    - Canamusali (Box 4)
    - Candido, Eustachio (Box 4)
    - Canon (Box 4)
    - Canones (Box 4)
    - Canter, Johannes (Box 4)
    - Canutus (*) (Box 4)
    - Capelluti (Box 4)
    - Capodilista (Box 4)
    - Carpani, Domenico de (Box 4)
    - Carrara, G.M.A. (Box 4)
    - Castroval (Box 4)
    - Cantinello (Box 4)
    - Cantone, Angelo (Box 4)
    - Cattani (Box 4)
    - Caza, Francesco (Box 4)
    - Cecco d'Ascoli (*) (Box 4)
    - Celcus (*) (Box 4)
    - Celtis, Conrad (Box 4)
    - Censorinus (Box 4)
    - Cermisone (*) (Box 5)
    - Champier (*) (Box 5)
    - Chappusot (Box 5)
    - Chiarini (Box 5)
    - Chromantia (Box 5)
    - Christophorus von Glotz (Box 5)
    - Cicero (Box 5)
    - Ciruelo (Box 5)
    - Clapis, Petrus Antonius de (Box 5)
    - Clementini (Box 5)
    - Cleomedes (Box 5)
    - Cleonides (Box 5)
    - Collenuccio (*) (Box 5)
    - Colombo (Box 5)
    - Columella (*) (Box 5)
    - Columbre, Augustino (Box 5)
    - Comparaison (Box 5)
    - Compendium (Box 5)
    - Compost (*) (Box 5)
    - Computi (Box 5)
    - Computus Chirdmetralis (Box 5)
    - Computus Cracoviensis (Box 5)
    - Computus Nurembergensis (Box 5)
    - Computus-Italian (Box 5)
    - Computus-German (Box 5)
    - Concoreggio (Box 5)
    - Conrad von Megenberg (*) (Box 5)
    - Conradus de Zabern (Box 5)
    - Contarini (Box 5)
    - Contenances (Box 5)
    - Cookery, Book of (Box 5)
    - Cornazano (Box 5)
    - Corti, Francesco (Box 5)
    - Corvinus, Laurentius (Box 5)
    - Corvo, Andrea (Box 5)
    - Cranstoun, David (Box 5)
    - Crescenzi, Pier de (Box 5)
    - Crispo, Girolamo (Box 5)
    - Christobal de Escobar (Box 5)
    - Calmacher, Philippus (Box 5)
    - Cursus (Box 5)
    - Cyclopius (*) (Box 5)
    - Danielis Somnia (Box 5)
    - Danser (Box 5)
    - Dati, Giuliano (Box 5)
    - Dati, Gregorio (Box 5)
    - Decembrio, Pietro (*) (Box 5)
    - Degui, Pedro (Box 5)
    - Perrames, Johannes (Box 5)
    - Descriptiones Morborum (Box 5)
    - Despars, Jacques (*) (Box 5)
    - Dialogus Linguae, Ventris (Box 5)
    - Diaz, Manuel (Box 5)
    - Diedo, Francesco (Box 5)
    - Dino del Garbo (*) (Box 5)
    - Diogenes (*) (Box 5)
    - Dionysios Periegetes (Box 5)
    - Dioscorides (*) (Box 5)
    - Directorium Humanae Vitae (Box 5)
    - Dobschitze (Box 5)
    - Dominicus de Flandria (Box 5)
    - Dondi, Jacopo de (*) (Box 5)
    - Dorland, Petrus (Box 5)
    - Drohobicz (Box 5)
    - Duns Scot, John (Box 5)
    - Duran, Domingo Marcos (Box 5)
    - Durante, Camillo (Box 5)
    - Duval, Robert (Box 5)
    - Eaux Artificielles (*) (Box 5)
    - Eck, Paulus (Box 5)
    - Egidio da Roma (Box 5)
    - Egkstain, Adam (Box 5)
    - Elisio (Box 5)
    - Enea Silvio (Box 5)
    - Engel, Johann (Box 5)
    - Epidemia (*) (Box 5)
    - Epist. Graecae (Box 5)
    - Erndorfer, Lucas (Box 5)
    - Ernst, Herzog von Bayern (Box 5)
    - Estwood, John (Box 5)
    - Etymology (Box 5)
    - Euclid (Box 5)
    - Everardus de Amersfordia (Box 5)
    - Falucci, Nicolo (*) (Box 5)
    - Eyb, Albricht (*) (Box 5)
    - Faber Barduvicensis (Box 5)
    - Faber, Wenzel (*) (Box 5)
    - Febris (*) (Box 5)
    - Fernando de Cordoba (Box 5)
    - Fernandez, Martin (Box 5)
    - Ferrari da Gradi (*) (Box 5)
    - Ferrari, Teofilo. (Box 5)
    - Finico, Marsiglio (*) (Box 5)
    - Fiera, Battista (Box 5)
    - Filefo, Francesco (Box 5)
    - Firmicus (Box 5)
    - Ellenbog, Ulrich (*) (Box 5)
    - Firmen de Beauval (Box 5)
    - Fisch und Vogelfang (Fish and Bird Catching) (Box 5)
    - Florence (Box 5)
    - Folz, Hans (Box 5)
    - Fonti, Bartolomeo (Box 5)
    - Francesch Sanct Climent (Box 5)
    - Dialogus, da Sene (Box 5)
    - Franzeschi, Raffaele (Box 5)
    - Francesco da Siena (Box 5)
    - Frontinus, Sextus Julius (Box 5)
    - Gaetano, da Thiene (Box 5)
    - Gaddesten, John of (*) (Box 5)
    - Galen (*) (Box 5)
    - Gentile da Foligno (*) (Box 5)
    - Grunpeck (*) (Box 5)
    - Gafori (Box 5)
    - Gallensis, Johannes (Box 5)
    - Gambiglione, Angelo (*) (Box 5)
    - Ganivet (Box 5)
    - Garcia, Pedro (Box 5)
    - Gazio, Antonio (Box 5)
    - Geber (Box 5)
    - Gellius, Aulus (Box 5)
    - Gemmati, Battista (Box 5)
    - H (Box 5)
    - I-J (Box 5)
    - Maccagni, Domenico (Box 5)
    - Military Series (Box 5)
    - Paulus de Middelburgo (Box 5)
    - Pietro d'Abano (*) (Box 5)
    - Pantaleone (*) (Box 5)
    - Petroleon (*) (Box 5)
    - Proliano (*) (Box 5)
    - Rusio, Lorenzo (Box 5)
    - Stoeffler, Johann and Pflaum, Jacob (Box 5)
    - Syllanus de Nigris (Box 5)
    - Thimon, Judaei (Box 5)
    - Trezzo (Box 5)
    - Ulsen to Widman "Complete Series" (Box 5)
    - Versehung von Leib (the body) (Box 5)
    - Zerbi, Gabriele (*) (Box 5)
  - Incunabula
    - Short Title Lists (Box 6)
    - Inquiries (Box 6)
    - Cultural Aspects of Medicine, General Science (Box 6)
    - La Mia Nuova Collezione di Mille Incunaboli (Box 6)
    - Typenregisteren (type registers) (Box 6)
    - Unfinished Notes (Box 6)
    - Rambling Notes (Box 6)
    - Authors' Names, Index (Box 6)
    - Incunabula lists- Herbals (Box 6)
    - Notes for Printers (Box 6)
    - Notes (Box 6)
    - Types and Founts (Box 6)
    - Printers and Towns (Box 6)
    - Printers and Publishers (Box 6)
    - Printing Contracts, Prices (Box 6)
    - "Gleanings from Incunabula of Science and Medicine" (*) (Box 6)
    - Hortus Sanit. (Box 6)
    - Scheme for Catalog (Box 6)
    - Various notes on Incunabula (Box 6)
    - Paleo Pathology (Box 6)
    - Articles in Press (Box 6)
    - Bibliographical and Literary Notices (Box 6)
    - Clippings (Box 6)
    - A-L Bibliographical Notices (Box 6)
    - M-Z Bibliographical Notices (Box 6)
    - Corrections? (Box 6)
    - 50 Incunabula not in America (Box 6)
    - Incunabula -Lists in American Libraries (Box 6)
    - Short Title List (Box 6)
  - Incunabula [and misc.?]
    - Au Musée d'Art et d'Histoire (Box 7)
    - "Introductory" (Box 7)
    - Philosophy, Art and Science (Box 7)
    - Bibliographic Notices-Ordnung der Gesundheit (Order of Health) (Box 7)
    - Misc. Notes (Box 7)
    - Bibliographical Notes (Box 7)
    - Incunabula -descriptions "not elsewhere given" (Box 7)
    - Various Authors, lists of works (Box 7)
    - Illustration and Ornamentation (Box 7)
    - Misc. Incunabula (Box 7)
    - Incunabula, Introductory (Box 7)
    - Notes (Box 7)
    - Valesco de Tarenta (*) (Box 7)
    - Granollachs, Bernat de (*) (Box 7)
    - Grapaldi, (*) Grassus, Gresemund, (*) Graziadei (Box 7)
    - Versified Incunabula (Box 7)
    - Illustrated books (Box 7)
    - Geography, Cartography, Navigation (Box 7)
    - Statistics (Box 7)
    - Groups, Astrologers to Witchcraft (Box 7)
    - Hunger Apuleius ( Gart ) (Box 7)
    - Ferrari da Gradi's "Practica" (*) (Box 7)
    - Macer Floridus (*) (Box 7)
    - Munzer, Hieronymus (Box 7)
    - Nicolaus Pol Doctor (*) (Box 7)
    - Ugo da Siena (*) (Box 7)
    - Misc., but grouped together (Box 7)
    - Bartolomeo Montagnana's Consilia (Box 8)
    - XV Century woodcuts (tracings) (Box 8)
    - Album of illustrations of woodcuts and plates (Box 8)
    - Macer Floridus ( Herbals/Incunabula ) (*) (Box 8)
    - Incunabula (Box 8)
    - Bibliographical Society of America (Box 8)
    - Die Alteste Schriftmusterblatt einer Deutscher Druckerei (The Oldest Handwritten Plates of the German Press) (Box 8)
    - Knapp, William I.: ALS to [Noah?] Porter, 3 ALS to José Francisco Carret (Box 8)
    - Misc. (Box 8)
    - Three Old Italian Prints at Erlanger Library (Box 8)
    - Incunabula in their Original Monastic Bindings (Box 8)
    - Catalog of Illustrated Books (Box 8)
    - Fine Incunabula and 16th C. books (Box 8)
    - Incunabula -checklist at Boston Medical Library (Box 8)
    - Incunabula at the Library of the College of Physicians of Philadelphia (Box 8)
  - Subject File III
    - Swiss-American Society for Cultural Relations (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: Solothurn (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: Einsiedeln (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: Altdorf (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: La Chaux-de-Fonds (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: St. Gallen (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: Les Terrasses, Nyon (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: Naturforschenden Gesellschaft (Box 9)
    - Schweizerische Gesellschaft fur Geschichte der Medizin und der Naturwissenschaften (Swiss Society for History of Medicine and the Natural Sciences) (Box 9)
    - Schweiz: Gesellschaft fur Urgischichte (Society for Pre-History) (Box 9)
    - Schweizerischen Naturforschenden Gesellschaft-statuten (Box 9)
    - Semaine Medicale Internationale en Suisse (Box 9)
    - Unidentified Note (Box 9)
    - Various Societies and Meetings, Swiss (Box 9)
    - International Congress of Medicine (Box 9)
    - International Congress of History of Medicine (Box 9)
    - Congress of the History of Science (Box 9)
    - 1907 How Far--? (Box 9)
    - International Congress of Hygiene (Box 9)
    - Congress of Libraries and Bibliography (Box 9)
    - Congress of Physiology (Box 9)
    - Internationale Kongresse fur Geschichtswissenschaft (International Congress for Historical Science) (Box 9)
    - Deutsche Gesellschaft fur Geschichte der Medezin und der Naturwissenschaft (Box 9)
    - International Congress on Tuberculosis (Box 9)
    - Gart 1-6 [minus #4] (Box 9)
    - Gart 9-15 (Box 9)
    - ACK on Gart 5,6,10;*Arbolayre (Box 9)
    - Herbarium Apulei (Box 9)
    - Herbarium Apulei 1930-1936 (Box 9)
    - Herbier le Grant (Box 9)
    - Herbarius (Box 9)
    - Herbarius Latinus (Box 9)
    - Herbals Incunabula (Box 9)
    - Herbals (Box 9)
    - Hortus (Box 9)